<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: DIY | Dreaming in Digital]]></title>
  <link href="http://dreaming-in-digital.me/blog/categories/diy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dreaming-in-digital.me/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-17T11:41:18+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://dreaming-in-digital.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Evan Hung]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[mail2evan@me.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AKG K518DJ detachable cable modification]]></title>
    <link href="http://dreaming-in-digital.me/blog/2012/04/22/akg-k518dj-single-entry-with-detachable-cable-modification/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T14:21:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://dreaming-in-digital.me/blog/2012/04/22/akg-k518dj-single-entry-with-detachable-cable-modification</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/518dj-2.jpg"></p>

<p>I like the design of Monster headphones, especially the detachable cable and it's cable design, but I don't appreciate it's sound quality and price tag. My AKG 518dj headphone is the best headphone in it's price range, but it also came with a long, old fashioned and undetachable cable. So I decide to modify it, make it's cable function just like Monsters, and then give it a Monster cable.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The modification is actually very easy. The AKG's headphone is well designed and it's very easy to open up, just remove the pads and there are 3 screws that hold each cup together. Untighten them and the cup will split in half, allowing you to get to the driver connections.</p>

<p><img src="/images/518dj-1.jpg"></p>

<p>The 3.5mm socket is from a Sony 3.5mm extension cable, it got an aluminum case, which looks very nice.  The gluing and soldering is very basic, but drilling a perfect hole for the socket is quite difficult. The cup is round shaped and 3.5mm socket must come out at a roughly 30 degree angle. It's impossible to precisely measure how much to drill, so I have to slow down the process, and do it very carefully.</p>

<p>After spending nearly 1 hour to drill the hole using a dremel, and fix the socket with hot glue, I finally got it done.</p>

<p><img src="/images/518dj-4.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="/images/518dj-5.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
